{
    "title": "CMDA Pharmacology Mock: Jan 2017",
    "author": "ayobami",
    "course": "pharmacology",
    "date": "2024-06-21 14:22",
    "description": "some questions in the matching section of a CMDA pharmacology mock",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "A non-selective adrenoceptor blocker with partial agonist activity",
            "answer": "Labetalol"
        },
        {
            "question": "Direct acting cholinomimetic that is lipid soluble and is favoured in the treatment of glaucoma",
            "answer": "pilocarpine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Drug of choice in the treatment of anaphylactic shock",
            "answer": "Epinephrine"
        },
        {
            "question": "A drug that prevents storage of acetylcholine in its vesicle",
            "answer": "vesamicol"
        },
        {
            "question": "Used to suppress premature labour",
            "answer": "Ritodrine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Can reduce the binding of aldosterone to its receptor",
            "answer": "spironolactone"
        },
        {
            "question": "Osmotic agent used to reduce intracranial pressure",
            "answer": "mannitol"
        },
        {
            "question": "Used for the treatment of edema associated with heart failure",
            "answer": "Furosemide"
        },
        {
            "question": "Causes hyperchloremic metabolic acidosis",
            "answer": "acetazolamide"
        },
        {
            "question": "Phase I clinical trials",
            "answer": "Open/non blind"
        },
        {
            "question": "Phase IV clinical trials",
            "answer": "Post-marketing surveillance"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sodium-glucose co-transporter-2 inhibitor",
            "answer": "canagliflozin"
        },
        {
            "question": "CYP450 inhibitor",
            "answer": "Ketoconazole"
        },
        {
            "question": "CYP450 inducer",
            "answer": "Phenytoin"
        },
        {
            "question": "A phase I metabolic reaction",
            "answer": "N-dealkylation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Elimination of constant amount of drug per unit time",
            "answer": "Zero-order elimination"
        },
        {
            "question": "A measure of how well a drug produces response",
            "answer": "Efficacy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Most common adverse effect of inhaled insulin",
            "answer": "Hypoglycemia"
        }
    ]
}
